Kaifeng Huang

D2007, Interdisciplinary Building No. 2, No. 2005 Songhu Rd., Shanghai

Email: kaifeng.h@icloud.com http://kaifeng-h.github.io

Last Updated: Setp. 15, 2022

I am currently a research fellow at Software Engineering Lab, Fudan University. I obtained my PhD from Fudan University in 2022, supervised by **Prof. Xin Peng** and **Prof. Bihuan Chen**. My research interests focus on software engineering, OSS supply chain and software evolution.

EDUCATION

• Fudan University

Shanghai, China

PhD of Software Engineering

Sept. 2016 - Jan. 2022

Thesis: Third-Party Library Harmonization and Update Recommendation based on API Analysis.

• Donghua University

Shanghai, China

Bachelor of Electronics Engineering

Sept. 2012 - July. 2016

Experience

• Research Fellow

Shanghai, China

Software Engineering Lab, Fudan University

Jan 2022 - Present

o I am very proud to work with **Prof. Bihuan Chen** and co-mentor a group of brilliant students to conduct researches on interesting topics.

• Visiting Student

Singapore

Nanyang Technological University

Aug. 2017 - Oct. 2017

o I visited Singapore while I was a PhD student. I was very honored to be mentored by **Prof. Yang Liu** and get acquainted with a group of excellent research scholars.

Publications

Tracking Patches for Open Source Software Vulnerabilities.

Congying Xu, Bihuan Chen, Chenhao Lu, Kaifeng Huang, Xin Peng, and Yang Liu. In Proceedings of the 30th ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, Singapore, accepted, 2022.

Characterizing Usages, Updates and Risks of Third-Party Libraries in Java Projects. Kaifeng Huang, Bihuan Chen, Congying Xu, Ying Wang, Bowen Shi, Xin Peng, Yijian Wu, and Yang Liu. Empirical Software Engineering, 2022. (An invited extended version of the ICSME'20 paper)

• RepFinder: Finding Replacements for Missing APIs in Library Update. Kaifeng Huang, Bihuan Chen, Linghao Pan, Shuai Wu, and Xin Peng. In Proceedings of the 36th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering, Melbourne, Australia, 2021, p266-278

• Interactive, Effort-Aware Library Version Harmonization.
Kaifeng Huang, Bihuan Chen, Bowen Shi, Ying Wang, Congying Xu, and Xin Peng. In Proceedings of the 28th ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, Sacramento, California, United States, 2020, p518-529.

An Empirical Study of Usages, Updates and Risks of Third-Party Libraries in Java Projects. Ying Wang, Bihuan Chen, Kaifeng Huang, Bowen Shi, Congying Xu, Xin Peng, Yijian Wu and Yang Liu. In Proceedings of the 36th IEEE International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution, Adelaide, Australia, 2020, p35-45.

CLDIFF: Generating Concise Linked Code Differences.

Kaifeng Huang, Bihuan Chen, Xin Peng, Daihong Zhou, Ying Wang, Yang Liu, and Wenyun Zhao. In Proceedings of the 33rd IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering, Montpellier, France, 2018, p679-690.

• DesignDiff: Continuously Modeling Software Design Difference from Code Revisions. Xiao Wang, Lu Xiao, Kaifeng Huang, Bihuan Chen, Yutong Zhao, and Yang Liu. In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Software Architecture, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil, 2020, p179-190.

AWARDS AND FELLOWSHIPS

- Outstanding Graduate of Fudan University, 2022
- Super-PostDoctoral Fellowship, Fudan University, 2021
- Scholarship of Academic Excellence, Fudan University, 2021
- Scholarship of Academic Excellence, Fudan University, 2020
- IEEE TCSE Distinguished Paper Award, 2020
- CCF Prototype Competition 2rd Prize, 2020
- Scholarship of Academic Excellence, 2019
- National Scholarship, Fudan University, 2018
- ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Award, 2018
- CCF Prototype Competition 2rd Prize, 2018
- Scholarship of Academic Excellence, 2017
- Shanghai Outstanding Graduate, 2016

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, C/C++, Bash, Latex.
- Tools: JDT, JavaParser, Soot, Git.